<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./hdf5reader.png" type="Source">
	<name>HDF5 Reader</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Reads dataSets and attributes from an HDF5 File.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node reads dataSets and attributes from an HDF5 File.
			The columns in the output table will be created by the dataSets and
			the flow variables by the attributes. Both will be named by the
			path within the file. 
		</intro>

		<tab name="File Chooser">
			<option name="Input file">
				Select the path to the input file.
			</option>
			<br />
			<option name="Fail if rowSize differs">
				Specifies if the node fails for missing values. Missing values
				appear if the first dimension of the dataSet, which is the
				rowSize of the columns in the output, is not equal for every
				column. So the node fails at the first difference in the
				rowSize.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="DataSet Selector">
			Specifies the included and excluded dataSets of the file.
			<br />
			<br />
			The names of the dataSets are the paths within the file. The names
			of the columns additionally contain the dimensions in terms of
			their dimensions in the original dataSet without the first
			dimension which is considered as rowSize.
			<br />
			<br />
			So this is the content of the output table.
			<br />
			<br />
			The usage is based on the Column Filter.
		</tab>
		<tab name="Attribute Selector">
			Specifies the included and excluded attributes of the file.
			So these are converted to the flow variables of the output.
			<br />
			<br />
			The usage is also based on the Column Filter.
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Output table">
			All included dataSets merged together by columns. The first
			dimension of the dataSets will be interpreted as rowSize and the
			remaining dimensions as columns.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
